Guide to the Stanford Humanities Center Audiovisual Materials
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Humanities Center audiovisual materials
1989-2006
SC0827
Stanford Humanities Center.
3.5 Linear feet
Collection contains recordings of lectures, panels, round tables, and other events sponsored by the Stanford Humanities Center. Videotapes include a John Cage concert and lecture, 1992, a teachers' conference, 1992, and the film "Of Mixed Minds: A Portrait of the Stanford Humanities Center." Audiocassettes include the John Cage events, 1992; lectures by Martha Nussbaum, Kathleen Sullivan, Bliss Carnochan, Susan Sontag, J. M. Coetzee, Carlo Ginzburg, Lawrence Weiskrantz, Charles Bernstein, Pina Bausch, Bei Dao, Marjorie Garber, Homi Bhabha, Wolfgang Iser, Larry Levine, Thomas Crow, and Steven Pinker. Other events on audiocassette include the colloquium "What's Left of Enlightenment?," 1997; talks and discussions from "Shape of the Humanities #2: Philosophy and Other Humanities," 1999; and the symposium "Whitehead's Account of the Sixth Day" with Isabelle Stengers, Donna Haraway, and Richard Rorty, 2006 [on CD].
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Access: some items may need to be reformatted prior to use.
Description of the Collection
Collection contains recordings of lectures, panels, round tables, and other events sponsored by the Stanford Humanities Center. Videotapes include a John Cage concert and lecture, 1992, a teachers' conference, 1992, and the film "Of Mixed Minds: A Portrait of the Stanford Humanities Center." Audiocassettes include the John Cage events, 1992; lectures by Martha Nussbaum, Kathleen Sullivan, Bliss Carnochan, Joseph Brodsky, Susan Sontag, J. M. Coetzee, Carlo Ginzburg, Lawrence Weiskrantz, Charles Bernstein, Pina Bausch, Bei Dao, Marjorie Garber, Homi Bhabha, Wolfgang Iser, Larry Levine, Thomas Crow, and Steven Pinker. Other events on audiocassette include the colloquium "What's Left of Enlightenment?," 1997; talks and discussions from "Shape of the Humanities #2: Philosophy and Other Humanities," 1999; and the symposium "Whitehead's Account of the Sixth Day" with Isabelle Stengers, Donna Haraway, and Richard Rorty, 2006 [on CD].
Access Terms
Bausch, Pina.; Beidao, 1949-; Bernstein, Charles, 1950-; Bhabha, Homi K., 1949-; Brodsky, Joseph, 1940-1996; Cage, John; Carnochan, W. B.; Coetzee, J. M., 1940-; Crow, Thomas E., 1948-; Garber, Marjorie B.; Ginzburg, Carlo.; Haraway, Donna Jeanne.; Iser, Wolfgang.; Levine, Larry.; Nussbaum, Martha Craven, 1947-; Rorty, Richard.; Sontag, Susan, 1933-; Stanford Humanities Center.; Stengers, Isabelle.; Sullivan, Kathleen M., 1955-; Weiskrantz, Lawrence.; Audiotapes.; Humanities; Videorecordings.
Collection Contents
- Audiovisual material, Accession ARCH-2006-142
  - John Cage
    - John Cage LECTURE, “Here Comes Everybody: Overpopulation and Art.”, Jan. 28, 1992; 1.1; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
    - John Cage Lecture + Violin, Jan. 29, 1992; 1.2; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
    - John Cage Panel 1, January 28, 1992; 1.4; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
    - John Cage Panel 2, January 28, 1992; 1.5; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
    - John Cage PANEL, Jan. 29, 1992; 1.6; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
    - John Cage Concert II, Jan. 31, 1992; 1.7; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
    - John Cage at Stanford: Kathan Brown and John Cage in conversation. January 27, 1992. Master tape, 3.1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Cage: Overpopulation and Art. Master tape., January 28, 1992; 3.2; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 3)
    - Cage: Overpopulation and Art. John Cage – Kresge Aud., 1/28/92; 3.3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - John Cage, Overpopulation and Art. Copy, 1/28/92; 3.4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Cage Discussion, Campbell Recital Hall. Tape 1 of 2, 1/28/92; 3.5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Cage Discussion Campbell Recital Hall. Tape 2 of 2, 1/28/92; 3.6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - John Cage Panel "The Making of Americans." Master Tape. Tape 1 of 2, Jan. 28, 1992; 3.7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Cage Panel "The Making of Americans." Master Tape. Tape 2 of 2, Jan. 28, 1992; 3.8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Cage Panel. Pt. II. Cage Tues. Panel II, 1/28/1992; 3.9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Cage Panel Discussion, Campbell Recital Hall. Master Tape. Tape 1 of 2, /29/92; 3.10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Cage Open Panel. Master. Tape 1 of 2, Jan. 30, 1992; 3.12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Cage Open Panel (conclusion). Master. Tape 2 of 2, Jan. 30, 1992; 3.13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Cage Panel Discussion, Campbell Recital Hall, 1/29/92; 3.11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Cage Panel Discussion, Campbell Recital Hall. Copy. Tape 1 of 2, 1/30/92; 3.14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Cage Panel Discussion, Campbell Recital Hall. Copy. Tape 2 of 2, 1/30/92; 3.15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Cage Lecture, Dinkelspiel Auditorium. "Overpopulation and Art.". Master Tape, Jan. 30, 1992; 3.16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - John Cage, Dinkelspiel Auditorium. James Joyce/Marcel Duchamp/Erik Satie: An Alphabet., Jan. 31, 1992; 3.17; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Performing Cage, Dinkelspiel Auditorium. Nocturne; Eight Whiskus; Music for Five; Aria; Quartets for Orchestra; James Joyce/Marcel Duchamp/Erik Satie: An Alphabet (recorded from room mics). Master Tape. Tape 1 of 2, January 31, 1992; 3.18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Performing Cage, Dinkelspiel Auditorium. James Joyce/MarcelDuchamp/Erik Satie: An Alphabet (cont.). Master Tape. Tape 2 of 2., January 31, 1992; 3.19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Musicircus on _____; Lunch with John Cage. Master tape, 1/31/92; 3.20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Cage: Musicircus + Mvoyce, 1992?; 3.21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Bliss Carnochan Lectures
    - Thomas Crow, "The Scandals of Allegory: How Do Warhols Mean?", 2003 Apr 25; 3.92; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Thomas Crow. 1 of 2, 2003 Apr 25; 3.90; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 3)
    - Thomas Crow, 2 of 2, 2003 Apr 25; 3.91; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 3)
    - Thomas Crow, Levinthal Hall, 3:30 PM. Tape 1 of 2, 2003 Apr 25; 3.93; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 3)
    - Thomas Crow, Levinthal Hall, 3:30 PM. Tape 1 of 2, 2003 Apr 25; 3.94; 1 audiocassette(s) (DAT) (Box 3)
    - Larry Levine: "All the Nations in the World: The Search for American Identity.", February 28, 1995; 3.87; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Levinthal Distinguished Speaker Lectures
    - J.M. Coetzee "The Poets and the Animals.", October 29, 1997; 3.32; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - J. M. Coetzee "The Philosophers and the Animals.", October 23, 1997; 3.31; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Susan Sontag "Rethinking the Novel.", April 10, 1996; 3.29; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - Susan Sontag "Cruelty and Apathy" at Kresge Auditorium, April 16, 1996; 3.30; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Shape of the Humanities
    - #2: Philosophy and the Other Humanities. " ‘Philosophy and Its Other' with Judith Butler and Richard Rorty." Tape #1, Panel #1., January 29, 1999; 3.51; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - #2: Philosophy and the Other Humanities. " ‘Philosophy and Its Other' with Judith Butler and Richard Rorty." Tape #2, Panel #1, January 29, 1999; 3.52; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - #2: Philosophy and the Other Humanities. " ‘Classical Philosophy and its Contents' with John Cooper and Josiah Ober" Tape #3, Panel #2, January 29, 1999; 3.53; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - #2: Philosophy and the Other Humanities. " ‘Classical Philosophy and its Contents' with John Cooper and Josiah Ober" Tape #4, Panel #2, January 29, 1999; 3.54; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - #2: Philosophy and the Other Humanities. " ‘What Counts as Philosophy' with Sepp Gumbrecht and John Perry." Tape #5, Panel #3., January 29, 1999; 3.55; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - #2: Philosophy and the Other Humanities. " ‘What Counts as Philosophy' with Sepp Gumbrecht and John Perry." Tape #6, Panel #3, January 29, 1999; 3.56; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - #2: Philosophy and the Other Humanities. " ‘Philosophy and/or Intellectual History' with Lawrence Dickey and Allen Wood" Tape #7, Panel #4, January 30, 1999; 3.57; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - #2: Philosophy and the Other Humanities. " ‘Philosophy and/or Intellectual History' with Lawrence Dickey and Allen Wood." Tape #8, Panel #4, January 30, 1999; 3.58; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - #2: Philosophy and the Other Humanities. "Roundtable Discussion with Robert Harrison, Lanier Anderson, Thomas Grey, Kenneth Taylor" Tape #9, January 30, 1999; 3.59; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - #3, Panel 1, Tape 1, April 23, 1999; 3.61; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - #3, Panel 1, Tape 2, April 23, 1999; 3.62; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - #3, Panel 2, Tape 1, April 23, 1999; 3.63; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - #3, Panel 2, Tape 2, April 23, 1999; 3.64; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - #3, Panel 3, Tape 1, April 23, 1999; 3.65; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - #3, Panel 3, Tape 2, April 23, 1999; 3.66; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - #3, Roundtable, Tape 1, April 24, 1999; 3.67; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
    - #3, Roundtable, Tape 2, April 24, 1999; 3.68; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - "It Doesn't Get Any Better Than This", 8/12/89; 1.3; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Humanities Center Teachers' Conference, 1.8; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Teachers Conference #1, 5/14/92; 1.9; 1 videotape (Betacam SP) (Box 1)
  - Teachers Conference #2, 5/12/92; 1.10; 1 videotape (Betacam SP) (Box 1)
  - Teachers Conference #3, Asian-American hist., 5/12/92; 1.11; 1 videotape (Betacam SP) (Box 1)
  - Teachers Conference #4, Asian-American hist., Interview #1 (Mariposa House), 5/12/92; 2.1; 1 videotape (Betacam SP) (Box 2)
  - FSLT Summer Drama Program, 7-10-92; 2.2; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - FS Summer Drama Program, 7-31-92; 2.3; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - "Free to Be, You and Me" -- Sir Francis Drake School and Hunter's Point Youth Park; Directed by: Elena Melendez, 7/29/92; 2.4 (Box 2)
  - "Flying High" Children in the Arts Project – Marshell Jones?, 1992?; 2.5; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Of Mixed Minds: A Portrait of the Stanford Humanities Center. Copy 1 of 4., 1993; 2.6; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Of Mixed Minds: A Portrait of the Stanford Humanities Center. Copy 2 of 4., 1993; 2.7; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Of Mixed Minds: A Portrait of the Stanford Humanities Center. Copy 3 of 4., 1993; 2.8; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Of Mixed Minds: A Portrait of the Stanford Humanities Center. Copy 4 of 4; master?, 1993; 2.9; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Of Mixed Minds. Copy 5, 1993; 4.10; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - Open Knowledge '04, October 18, 2004; 2.10; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 2)
  - Musicircus/Mvoyce, 1992?; 3.22; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - CSP Class: "American Avant-Garde" Continuing Studies Class with Danny Herwitz. Master Tape, Feb. 6, 1992; 3.23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Sexton Forum I. A., 3.24; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Tavener: The Protecting Veil. Yo-Yo Ma. Tavener: The Hidden Measure, 3.25; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Martha Nussbaum "Pity and Compassion." Copy, January 21, 1993; 3.26; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Kathleen Sullivan "Free Speech Flip-Flop.", Feb. 9, 1995; 3.27; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - "The Humanities Center at Stanford: How it Came About and Why" by Bliss Carnochan. The Stanford Historical Society., February 1998; 3.28; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Carlo Ginzburg "The Dialogic Dimension of Jesuit Historiography." [Marta Sutton Weeks Visiting Scholars lecture]. Master. Tape 1 of 2, January 25, 1994; 3.33; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Carlo Ginzburg "The Dialogic Dimension of Jesuit Historiography." [Marta Sutton Weeks Visiting Scholars lecture]. Master. Tape 2 of 2, January 25, 1994; 3.34; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - What's Left of Enlightenment? [a colloquium], Hartly Conf. Rm. Tape 1 of 2, January 24, 1997; 3.35; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - What's Left of Enlightenment? [a colloquium], Hartly Conf. Rm.. Tape 2 of 2, January 24, 1997; 3.36; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - What's Left of Enlightenment? [a colloquium] AM session, January 25, 1997; 3.37; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - What's Left of Enlightenment? [a colloquium] PM session. Tape 1 of 2, January 25, 1997; 3.38; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - What's Left of Enlightenment? [a colloquium] PM session. Tape 2 of 2, January 25, 1997; 3.39; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Charles Bernstein. [part of "Visual Poetics" lecture series], January 13, 1998; 3.44; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Gender Poster for Web. No date given. [Image file of poster; same sleeve as Prez Lec/Humanities Center], 3.89; 1 optical disc(s) (CD) (Box 3)
  - Pinker, Steven, Lecture from "Story, Metaphor, Vision: Cognitive Science and the Humanities" conference., 11/10/2004; 3.95; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Sweetser Powerpoint from CogSci and Humanities Conference, November 12, 2004; 3.96; 1 optical disc(s) (CD-R) (Box 3)
  - Douglas Hofstadter Discussion, Levinthal Hall, Feb. 7, 2006; 3.100; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - #1 lunch conversations, May 1992; 4.1; 1 videotape(s) (Betacam) (Box 4)
  - #2 [no information on label], May 1992; 4.2; 1 videotape(s) (Betacam) (Box 4)
  - #3 [no information on label], May 1992; 4.3; 1 videotape(s) (Betacam) (Box 4)
  - #4 Larry Friedlander, May 1992; 4.4; 1 videotape(s) (Betacam) (Box 4)
  - #5 Brian Rotman, May 1992; 4.5; 1 videotape(s) (Betacam) (Box 4)
  - #6 Kathleen Canning, May 1992; 4.6; 1 videotape(s) (Betacam) (Box 4)
  - #7 Anna Zentella and Felicity Nussbaum, May 1992; 4.7; 1 videotape(s) (Betacam) (Box 4)
  - #8-10 Edward Said interview, May 1992; 4.8; 1 videotape(s) (Betacam) (Box 4)
  - Edward Said Interviews, Spring 1992; 4.9; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)
  - Hazel Carby, October 2003; 5.1; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 5)
  - Slides used in Bei Dao's talk, Nov. 24, 1999; 5.2 (Box 5)
- Audiovisual material, Accession ARCH-2007-237
  - Tapes 1-4 (on one cassette): lunch with Natalie Davis; Larry Friedlander interactive video demo, 5/5/92; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Tape 5B campus views without commentary, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Tape 6B Window Dup: shots of campus, Marisposa House & staff, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Tapes 9-12 (on one cassette): Edward Siad; Edward Siad/Sandra Greene; Greene/Hayles, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Tape 16 Interview with Carnochan on SHC, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Tape 17 Interview with Wanda Corn on SHC, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Tape 18 [labeled "Humanities Review"] Interview with Wanda Corn on SHC cont'd, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Tape 19 Roundtable discussion: Charlie [Junkerman?], Wanda, Marleen Rosmond, Harry [illeg], Michael Fellman, Colin Palmer, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Tape 20 Roundtable discussion #2 at Mariposa House: SHC in academic and student life, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Tape 21 Roundtable discussion #3, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Tape 22 Mural: students (not SU) commenting on meaning of mural, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Tape 23 Mural: students (not SU) commenting on meaning of mural, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Tape 24 Interview with Charles Junkerman re SHC, its role at SU and nationally, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Tape 25 Interview with Charles Junkerman cont'd and stills, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Bliss Carnochan's going away party, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Stanford Humanities Center Opening Gala, 16 October 2001; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 2)
  - Steven Pinker lecture, 11/10/04; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 2)
  - Anthony Grafton (2 lectures) and Douglas R. Hofstadter (1 lecture) on 1 disc, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 2)
  - Carnochan Lecture by Max Byrd, 4/20/07; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 2)
  - 5 minute intros, 10/4/04; 2.20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - 5 minute intros, 2004 Oct 1, 30; 2.21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
- Audiovisual material, 1992; Accession ARCH.2011-076
  - Brodsky, Joseph, poetry reading, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Brodsky, Joseph: open conversation, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Brodsky, Joseph: Clio, 1992 Oct 27; 1 audiocassette(s)
  - Brodsky, Joseph, on Hardy and Frost, 1992; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)